Guide to the Bernard F. Burgunder Collection of George Bernard Shaw, [ca. 1810]-1990.
Bernard F. Burgunder Collection of George Bernard Shaw, [ca. 1810]-1990.
- Series XVI. Miscellany Media
  - Shaw. Spoken English and Broken English. Record and Booklet., [n.d.]; SR-10337-10338 (Box 120)
    Two 33 1/3 rpm vinyl record written and spoken by Bernard Shaw with printed booklet explaining the records, produced by the Linguaphone Institute, London.
  - (Copy 2) Shaw. Spoken English and Broken English. Record and Booklet., [n.d.]; SR-10339-10340 (Box 120)
    (Copy 2) Two 33 1/3 rpm vinyl record written and spoken by Bernard Shaw with printed booklet explaining the records, produced by the Linguaphone Institute, London.
  - Bernard Shaw, 1856-1950: Some of his Broadcasts. Record., [n.d.] (Box 120)
    One vinyl 33 1/3 repm. The recordings of Shaw from the Archives of the BBC, produced by the BBC Radio Enterprises.
  - Bernard Shaw speaks. Record, 1937 (Box 120)
    One 33 1/3 vinyl record. A 1937 short wave broadcast on the topics of war, nature, divine providence, Beethoven, emotional experience, woman, primitive societies, pacifist, Lincoln, are we lovable animals?, sending the old to war, civilization, Russia and north America, the class war, and four hour day. Produced by Heritage Productions.
  - The Shaw-Terry Letters, 1959 (Box 120)
    Read by Dame Peggy Ashcroft and Cyril Cusack; adapted and directed by Howard Sackler. Produced by Caedmon publishers; 1 record.
  - By George. Record., [n.d.] (Box 120)
    Starring Max adrian as Bernard Shaw; devised by Michael Voysey. A 2 record set produced on Angel Records, Capitol Records; in box
  - The Story-Teller ... a Session with Charles Laughton. Record, [n.d.] (Box 120)
    A 2 record set of on-stage performances, including Shaw's "Major Barbara," and other favorite Laughton readings and stories. Produced by Capitol Records.
- Series XVII. Museum Items
  - Mrs. Jenny Patterson miniature (Box 122)
    By Robert James Halls, painted on ivory. Shaw's first lover, a widow 15 his senior and friend of his aunt, Arabella Gillmore.
  - Arabella Gillmore Miniature by Robert James Halls. (Box 122)
    By Robert James Halls, painted on ivory. Judy Muster's mother
  - John Duke Gillmore Miniature by Robert James Halls. (Box 122)
    By Robert James Halls, painted on ivory.. Judy Muster's father.
  - John Duke Gillmore Photograph (Box 122)
    Not identified with certainty.
  - Walter Gillmore Photograph (Box 122)
    In leather frame, thought to be Walter, Judy Muster's brother, killed in 1902.
  - Lady wearing brooch Photograph (Box 122)
    In closed case, wearing a theosophical brooch.
  - Judy Muster's Photograph (Box 122)
    Sitting in a garden
  - G.B.S.'s writing case (Box 122)
    Brown leather bag with straps and lock; leather carrying case inside, with pockets for other items stitched on.
  - Harold Musters Writing Case (Box 122)
    Brown leather case "H.C.M." in gothic script on front.
  - Bronze cast of G. Bernard Shaw bust by Clare Winsten, MU-2846
    Bronze cast of Winsten's sculpture. Winsten also sculpted the statue of St. Joan in Shaw's garden, as well as illustrated Shaw's "Bouyant Billions" and "My Dear Dorothea". Currently in the RMC reference room.
  - Photographs and publicity materials relating to G. Bernard Shaw bust by Clare Winsten, 1946, 1971 (Box 124)
    Photographs of the 1946 bust of Shaw by Clare Winsten, including a photo of the bust being viewed by Princess Anne and the Mayor of the London Borough of Camden at the official opening of St. Pancras Library and Shaw Theatre on April 2, 1971. Also, the Order of Proceedings for the opening, the Camden Journal issue for April/May 1971, and a flyer on the National Youth Theatre (which provided informal entertainment at the opening). A letter from Shaw to Stephen Winsten suggesting that his wife Clare create the bust (June 13, 1946) is in Box 17. A letter from William R. Maidment, London Borough of Camden, to Mr. and Mrs. Winsten concerning the 1971 opening and the bust is in Box 27.
  - Mrs. Jenny Patterson portrait, unframed., 1885 (Mapcase-folder 1)
    Pastel by Robert Anning Bell. Shaw's affair with Jenny Patterson, his first lover, lasted from 1885 until 1893.
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Bound Manuscripts - cataloged individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections
Bd.Ms.1, AM Address Book. c. 1920-1950
Bd.Ms.2 +, TM Alps and Balkans [Later known as Arms and the Man]. 1894
Bd.Ms.3 +++, Androcles and the Lion Costume and Properties Drawings. 1912
Bd.Ms.4 +, Arms and the Man scriptbook for Captain Bluntschli. 1894
Bd.Ms.5 ++, TM & Proofs The Artstruck Englishman. 1917
Bd.Ms.6 +, Shaw Scrapbook. 1904-1913
Bd.Ms.7 ++, Candida items. March 1895
Bd.Ms.8 +, TM Caesar and Cleopatra Prologue. 1912
Bd.Ms.9 +, TM[copy] Chance-Medley. 1936
Bd.Ms.10 +, Scrapbook of Newspaper Clippings. 1913
Bd.Ms.11 +, Miscellaneous Clippings File. 1884-1944
Bd.Ms.12, Shaw's Dublin Testimonial. 1878
Bd.Ms.13 ++, Elgar, Edward T[printed]M of The Severn Suite. 1931
Bd.Ms.14 ++, Shaw. AM Evans, An Appreciation. 1903
Bd.Ms.15 ++, Farleigh, John D[woodcuts] The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search for God. 1932
Bd.Ms.16 ++, Ewens, Eric TM Shaw's First Play. September 1965
Bd.Ms.17-18 +, Books From Shaw's Library. October 1970
Bd.Ms.19 ++, Shaw TM & Printed Geneva. 1938
Bd.Ms.20, Shaw AM Getting Married. 1907-1908
Bd.Ms.21, Shaw's Glass Photo. c. 1920
Bd.Ms.22 ++, Shaw TM How to Become a Musical Critic. 1960
Bd.Ms.23, Shaw Printed M How to Become a Musical Critic. 1960
Bd.Ms.24 +, Shaw's Music Reviews. 1960
Bd.Ms.25 ++, D Inventory & Valuation of Property at 10 Adelphi Terrace W.C., London. 1908
Bd.Ms.26 +, Shaw TL & AL to Lord Kennet of the Dene.c. 1922
Bd.Ms.27 ++, Shaw AM[fragment] The Irrational Knot. 1886
Bd.Ms.28 +, Shaw TL[carbon] to Charlotte (Payne-Townshend) Shaw. 1896-1934
Bd.Ms.29, "Leonora" A[note] to Shaw. July 1878
Bd.Ms.30-31 ++, Shaw AM[fragment] Love Among the Artists. 1900
Bd.Ms.32 ++, Shaw D Man and Superman. June-July 1903
Bd.Ms.33 +, "Masks and Faces" Picture Play Scrapbook. 1917
Bd.Ms.34 ++, Scrapbook of Shaw Clippings. 1892-1895
Bd.Ms.35 ++, Shaw Printed Music in London. 1891-1894
Bd.Ms.36 ++, Shaw AM Musical Themes from Wagner. c. 1885
Bd.Ms.37 ++, Shaw TMS Conscientious Objectors. May 1916
Bd.Ms.38, O'Connor, Mrs. T. P. AM & Printed "Bernard Shaw's Superman Manuscript". April 1929
Bd.Ms.39, Shaw AM Political Science Lecture Note. April 11, 1933
Bd.Ms.40 +, Shaw AM Honour to J. T. Grein Speech. 1928
Bd.Ms.41 ++, Shaw TL[carbon] to Molly Tompkins. 1921-1940
Bd.Ms.42 +, Gene Tunney Letters. 1929-1940
Bd.Ms.43 ++, TM The Upanishads. Undated
Bd.Ms.44 +, Burgunder, Bernard F. AM & TM Desiderata Lists. Undated
Bd.Ms.45 +, Wells, Geoffrey H. Printed Bibliography of the Books and Pamphlets of George Bernard Shaw. 1928
Bd.Ms.46 ++, Bernard Shaw manuscript fragments of "Widowers' houses". 1884-1892
Bd.Ms.47 +, Shaw A[shorthand]M The Worst Journey in the World Postscript. 1948
Bd.Ms.48 +, Shaw TM The Garden of Eden [In the Beginning]. 1918
Bd.Ms.49 +, Deruelle, Marcel TM G.B. Shaw als Dramaturg. 1922
Bd.Ms.50 ++, Motoring Papers and Pictures. 1908-1939
Bd.Ms.51 ++, Letter to Lee Keedick. December 30, 1918